

PROFILE

Motivated young professional ready to advance my programming career as a Developer. I plan to continue developing my programming skills in advanced courses in both front and back-end technologies while working full-time. I am experienced in working in teams and contributing to the entire group's performance. I also have broad customer services experiences which I will combine with my developer skills to create new technology solutions that create great customer experiences. I am passionate about coding and the ability to create new solutions and applications for businesses.

CONTACT

PHONE:

281-794-8281

Address:

5356 Forbs Ln Bulverde, TX 78163

PORTFOLIO:

https://jpick77.github.io/JP-Portfolio/

CERTIFICATE:

DU Diploma.pdf

EMAIL:

Jpickron30@gmail.com

HOBBIES

Extreme Skiing Mountain Biking Soccer

JACOB PICKRON

Full Stack Developer

EDUCATION

The University of Denver – Full Stack Developer Program

October 2022 – April 2023 Certified Full Stack Developer

RH Health Services

June 2019 – December 2019 Emergency Medical Technician Training San Antonio, Texas

Alamo Community College (San Antonio) & Colorado Mountain College (Breckenridge)

September 2017 – May 2019 Basic College Courses

WORK EXPERIENCE

Golftec | Developer Contractor

March 2023 to Present

- Developed and implemented server-side APIs for their website
- De-bugged back-end code for the front-end team

Vail Resorts | Mountain Safety

November 2017 to April 2020

- Worked in teams to set up the ski runs with safety zones and monitor areas for dangerous activity to prevent accidents
- Reported accidents to Operations, monitored the injured skier, and provided basic medical attention until Ski Patrol arrived
- Patrolled ski areas to ensure patrons were safe, and cleared ski areas ahead of severe weather and as part of shutdown operations

King Sooper | Store Associate

January 2018 to August 2019

- Greeted customers, helped locate merchandise, and assisted them with their unique needs throughout the entire visit
- Managed product descriptions, store placement, and promotions to ensure positive customer experiences
- Operated the point of sale and fresh food preparation processes

SKILLS

- Used MongoDB to create a back-end social media application where a user shares their thoughts, react to friends' thoughts, and create a friend list. I used Express.js for routing, a MongoDB database, and the Mongoose ODM.
- Used JavaScript to create an application that an employee can use to generate a random password based on criteria they have selected. This app runs in the browser, and features dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by JavaScript.
- Used React to create my SPA portfolio, and most of my other projects.
- Built a command-line application from scratch to manage a company's employee database, using Node.js, Inquirer, and MySQL.
- Front-end languages: HTML5, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap.
- Used Web API to build a timed coding quiz with multiple-choice questions.
 This app runs in the browser and features dynamically updated HTML and
 CSS powered by JavaScript code.

- Created a simple calendar application using Third-party APIs that allows a
 user to save events for each hour of the day. This app runs in the browser
 and features dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by jQuery.
- Used Node.js to write server-side code using JavaScript.
- created an application called Note Taker that can be used to write and save notes. The application will use an Express.js back end and will save and retrieve note data from a JSON file.
- Used Object-Relational Mapping to build the back end for an e-commerce site. I used a working Express.js API and configured it to use Sequelize to interact with a MySQL database.
- Created a tech blog using the MVC paradigm in its architectural structure, using Handlebars.js as the templating language, Sequelize as the ORM, and the express-session npm package for authentication.
- Built a text editor using PWA. It features a number of data persistence techniques that serve as redundancy in case one of the options is not supported by the browser. The application also functions offline.
- I used a fully functioning Google Books API search engine to build a book search app built with a RESTful API and refactor it to be a GraphQL API built with Apollo Server. The app was built using the MERN stack, with a React front end, MongoDB database, and Node.js/Express.js server and API.